Blanca MANCILLA

4265, rue Jean-Brillant Montréal (Québec) H3T 1P2, Canada +1.514.591.2007

Email: blancalmancilla@gmail.com
Blog: superspreadsheet.wordpress.com
github: https://github.com/bluciam

Written, spoken: English, French, Spanish.

Other: German, B1 level, currently in Goethe Institut.



LinkedIn

Professional Profile

I have +10 years of experience in IT and over year and a half in Web development. I want to use my skills in design, documentation, coding, problem solving, leadership, mentorship and communication in a development team. I am always learning and experimenting with current technologies, attending MeetUps, reading or writing technical blogs, or on Twitter.

Current

2012–2015 Consultant, Montreal, Canada (Web developer and Technical Writer)

- · 1.5 years experience on Ruby on Rails
- · Front end development using CSS, bootstrap, HTML
- · External storage using Amazon Web Services, S3
- · *MailChimp* interface
- · Interaction with database APIs (postgresql, sqlite3)
- · Testing infrastructure using RSpec
- · User authentication using Devise
- · Software repositories in github and bitbucket
- · Excellent writing skills

Front-end example:

- http://vinka-creations.bitballoon.com

Back-end and front-end, testing phase:

- https://evening-harbor-6988.herokuapp.com

Computer skills snapshot

- · **Web programming** in Ruby on Rails, testing, CSS and Bootstrap, HTML.
- · **Open source** development tools, Linux, shell scripting, command line interface, git, github, bitbucket, ŁTŁX, software building tools, OpenStreetMap.
- **Teaching knowledge** in programming languages, C, object-oriented languages, Java, functional languages, Haskell, geographical information systems, ArcGIS, human computer interaction, information systems, computer graphics.
- · **Beginner** in JavaScript, JQuery, Python, Django.

SuperSpreadSheet (S³), https://github.com/bluciam/superspreadsheet

The purpose of this project was to demonstrate the use of contextual electronic documents: case study, the multi-spreadsheet. It covered conception, research, design and implementation.

Anita Conti Mapping Server, https://github.com/bluciam/anita-jsp-2005

The ACMS project was developed as a proof of concept. Development iterations had to accommodate the constant change of requirements, tools and research discoveries. It was successful in its purpose.

TransLucid Project, http://sourceforge.net/projects/translucid

As a team member, I was part of the design and planning stages of creating the TransLucid language. I devised the documentation structure and tailored it to different audiences. As the first user, I was the main interactive tester of the system.

Education

1999-2004	PhD, Computer Science, UNSW Australia, Sydney
1993-1995	MSc, Geomatic Sciences, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1992-1993	French as a second language, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1990	Seminar on Research, Summer Program, SUNY at Stony Brook, USA
1989-1991	BSc, Computer Electronic Science, Iona College, NY, USA
1984-1988	BEng, Computer Systems Engineering (four of five years), Industrial University of Santander (UIS), Colombia

Previous Positions

2004-2016	Faculty Member, UNSW Australia, Sydney
2009-2012	Faculty Member, University of Technology, Sydney (UTS), Australia
1993-1995	Student Assistant (Remote Sensing),
1991-1992	System Administrator, IBM AS/400, Electro-Alloys, NY, USA

Conference and Workshops Organization

2001-2002	International Conference on Distributed Communities on the Web, DCW 2002 Local Arrangements Chair: Webmaster; budget and conference manager.
2000-2002	Women in Computing, UNSW, Director and founder:
	Liaison between community stakeholders; conception of events.
2000-2003	Girls in Science and Technology Workshops (an Anita Borg initiative),
	Founder, organizer, host: HTML, lego mindstorms and iMovie workshops.

Publications, http://plaice.web.cse.unsw.edu.au/archive/BLM

Total	28	Books	1	Book Chapters	1
		Journal Articles	5	Theses	2
		Conference Articles	17	Compilations	2